《沙娜拉传奇》前情提要...
Previously on "The Shannara Chronicles"...
公主殿下  你确定你想践踏
Princess, are you sure you wanna step on
精灵族几千年的传统吗
thousands of years of Elvin tradition?
有规定女孩不能参加选拔赛吗
Is there a rule that says a girl can't run the Gauntlet?
你如果明天再记错步子
You lose count of your steps tomorrow,
那将会成为你人生中最短的半英里
it'll be the shortest half mile of your life.
打开这个
Open it...
曾经属于  你父亲
Belonged... to your father.
那是精灵石
They're Elfstones.
不  妈  不要离开我
No, Mom, don't leave me.
父亲  这个人类是谁
Father, who is this Human?
这位是亚拉农
This is Allanon...
帕瑞诺最后一个德鲁伊
the last Druid of Paranor.
作为国王  我欢迎你们加入神选之子
As king, I welcome you to the Order of the Chosen.
爷爷还是不跟我说话
Grandpa still hasn't spoken to me.
外面的世界很危险  威尔
The world outside is dangerous, Wil.
到处都是侏儒  巨魔和流浪者
It's full of Gnomes and Trolls and Rovers.
我还以为精灵会很聪明呢
I thought Elves were supposed to be smart.
我是个半精灵
I'm half-Elf.
显然没遗传到好的那半
Clearly the wrong half.
这比我想象的还要糟
It's much worse than I thought.
每片叶子象征着一只恶魔
Each leaf represents a single Demon.
一旦叶子开始凋落  黑暗中的生物
Once they begin to fall, the creatures of darkness
将会一个个从封印之地释放出来
will be released from the Forbidding, one by one.
把东西还给我
I need those back.
为什么  它们很值钱吗
Why? Are they valuable?
你的流浪者女孩早就走了
Your Rover girl is long gone.
你相信魔法吗  孩子
Do you believe in magic, boy?
当然不信
Of course not.
用你的双眼来见证
Let your eyes bear witness!
神选之子  他们都死了
The Chosen... they're all dead.
不  还有一个活着
No... one still lives.
下一刀将直接插进你的心脏
Next one goes straight through your heart!
你想怎样
What was your plan,
给我下药然后抢走东西吗
drug me and then rob me?
艾尔奎斯圣树快死了  你是唯一能救它的人
The Ellcrys is dying and you are the only one who can save it.
后退
Stay back!
快跑  安波莉  快跑
Run, Amberle! Run!
我们得马上走了
We have to go! Now!
我姑姑
My aunt!
她死了
She's gone.
不可能会这样的
This can't be happening.
-那是不是...-这是恶魔  一只怒鬼
- Is that... - It's a Demon. A Fury.
还会来更多的
There will be more coming.
我们得走了
We need to leave.
告诉我怎么回事
Tell me what's going on.
那东西是怎么找到我们的
How did that thing find us?
老实说  我也不知道
Honestly, I don't know.
根本就没人知道我们来这里了
No one even knew we were headed here.
岱达摩在宫里的眼线
The Dagda Mor's agent in the palace
会不惜一切代价铲除神选之子
will stop at nothing to finish off the Chosen.
铲除
Finish off?
其他人怎么样了
What happened to the others?
告诉我
Tell me!
他们都死了
They were murdered.
前天夜里的事
Two nights ago.
洛林呢
Lorin?
我们必须立即把你带回到艾尔奎斯圣树那里
We must take you to the Ellcrys immediately,
否则会有更多人死去
otherwise many more will die.
安波莉  等等
Amberle, wait!
这下可好了
Way to go.
别管我
Leave me alone.
不行
I can't.
这是德鲁伊的命令
Druid's orders.
我明白你的感受
I know how you feel.
我...
I, uh...
上周我母亲去世了
I lost my mom last week.
我想尽了各种办法...
I tried everything...
能找到的灵药和药方  我都找遍了
every elixir and potion I could get my hands on.
我以为我能挽回这一切
I thought I could fix it,
把她救回来
that I could save her,
可是...我办不到
but, uh... I couldn't.
我从没想过会这么思念一个人
I never knew it was possible to miss someone so much.
刚刚在悬崖那里  谢谢你
Back at the cliff... thank you.
你比看上去要勇敢
You're braver than you look.
可别把恐惧误认为勇敢了
Oh, don't mistake terror for bravery.
抱歉我没告诉你洛林的事
I'm sorry I didn't tell you about Lorin.
我害怕回阿博隆去
I'm afraid to go back to Arborlon.
为什么
Why?
因为艾尔奎斯圣树吗
Because of the Ellcrys?
因为我的所作所为
Because of what I did.
这是我造成的
I caused this.
亚拉农
Allanon...
德鲁伊洞穴...
The Druid cave...
带我去那里
take me here.
我止不了血
I can't stop the bleeding.
-我得缝合伤口  或者...-够了
- I need to suture it, or... - Enough.
你得立刻把她带回艾尔奎斯圣树那里
You must get her to the Ellcrys.
不  我不能丢下你
No, I'm not leaving you behind.
别管我  小子
Forget about me, boy.
你得保护好她
You must keep her safe.
亚拉农
Hey, hey, Allanon!
好吧  快走
All right, come on.
-你要去哪儿  -银河
- Hey, where are you going? - The Silver River.
那里的淤泥有治愈效果
Its mud is famed for its healing properties.
-我得陪着亚拉农  -不  你跟我一去去
- I should stay with Allanon. - No, you're coming with me.
我答应过他会保护你的
I promised him I'd protect you.
好吧
Okay.
很高兴看到你还算振作  孩子
Glad to see you're coping well, my son.
收到报告称  西境的精灵族农场和村庄
Had reports of attacks on Elvin farms and villages
遭到袭击
in the Westland.
恶魔干的
Demons.
有安波莉的消息了吗
Any word from Amberle?
我不该训练她参加选拔赛的
I should never have trained her for the Gauntlet.
你是溺爱她
You indulge her.
就跟她父亲溺爱你一样
Same way her father indulged you.
为了自己的弟弟
There was nothing that Aine would not do
艾尼什么都愿意去做
for his baby brother.
包括献出自己的生命
Including giving his life.
现在可不是缅怀伤痛的时候
Now is not the time to dredge up painful memories.
既然我们的罪孽又回来找我们索命
If our sins are coming back to kill us,
为什么我们不坦然面对呢
we might as well get them all on the table.
孩子  是侏儒杀了你哥哥  不是你
Son... Gnomes murdered your brother, not you.
你更希望当晚死的人是我
You wish it was me that died that night
而不是艾尼  对吗
instead of Aine, don't you?
知道吗  我每天也都是这么想的
See, I wish the same thing, every day.
-为什么是你  -你说什么
- Why you? - Excuse me?
为什么德鲁伊选你来保护我
Why did the Druid pick you to protect me?
不知道
No idea.
你知道你撒谎时耳朵会变红吗
Did you know your ears turn red when you lie?
我姓欧姆斯福德  据亚拉农所说
My last name is Ohmsford, but according to Allanon,
我是沙娜拉血脉的后人
I'm part of the Shannara bloodline.
等等  你是沙娜拉人
Wait, you're a Shannara?
简直难以置信
That's incredible.
每个精灵都熟知杰尔·沙娜拉的故事
Every Elf knows the story of Jerle Shannara by heart,
用魔法统一了四镜的最伟大战皇
the great warrior king who united the Four Lands with his magic.
是吗  沙迪谷里的人
Yeah, well, they didn't
并不怎么谈论这些事
talk about that very much out in the Vale.
那里没什么精灵崇拜者
Not a lot of Elf fans out here.
是啊  我也发现了
Yeah, I'm beginning to see that.
听着  我不是战士
Look, I'm no warrior.
我可以向你保证
And I can guarantee you
我的血脉中没有魔法存在
there's no magic running through these veins.
一旦把你和亚拉农
I'm heading to Storlock
送回王宫  我就要去司铎拉克了
as soon I get you and Allanon back to the palace.
要是我不想回去呢
What if I don't want to go back?
我可以帮你救德鲁伊  但在此之后
I'll help you save the Druid, but after that,
我悄悄离开对大家都好
it's better for everyone if I just disappear.
不  这不行  来吧
No, it's not. Come on.
就是这里
This is it.
银河
The Silver River.
我猜你会游泳吧
I assume you can swim?
要是你像我一样泡在水里长大
You get dunked as often as I did growing up,
你也能很快学会的
you learn pretty quick.
说好的"眼睛抬起来"呢
Hey, what happened to "Eyes up here"?
抱歉
Sorry.
安波莉
Amberle!
又在光着身子泡澡啊
Naked and wet again, I see.
埃蕾崔娅
Eretria!
你们认识吗
You two know each other?
你男朋友和我曾共度了一个奇妙的夜晚
Your boyfriend and I spent a magical night together.
那晚一点也不奇妙
That night was far from magical.
她给我下药  然后抢了我的东西
She drugged me, then robbed me blind.
把精灵石还给我
I need those Elfstones back!
放客气点  要不是我你早就死了
Be nice. If it wasn't for me, you'd be dead.
好吧  无论你跟我有什么恩怨
All right, whatever your issue with me,
先放安波莉走
let Amberle go.
没门
Not happening.
我跟这个精灵还有账没算呢
I've got unfinished business with this Elf.
在穿过森林的时候遇到的
Our paths crossed in the woods.
够了  该走了
Enough! Time to go.
埃蕾崔娅  求你了  我们有朋友快死了
Eretria, please, our friend is dying.
我得赶紧把这些淤泥敷到他的伤口上
I need to apply this mud to his wound before it's too late.
算你的朋友不走运了
Well, your friend's out of luck.
听着  有恶魔出现了
Look, there are Demons out there.
我知道这听起来很疯狂  但你得相信我
I know it sounds crazy, but you have to believe me.
它们随时会追上我们的
They could pick up our trail any minute.
恶魔  你当我傻吗
Demons? Do I look stupid?
确实傻
Actually, yes.
但他说的是真的
But he's telling the truth.
你觉得自己比我更高贵
You think you're better than me.
但在这外面  你什么也不是
But out here, you're nothing.
只是两条丧家犬
Just two stray dogs.
一个蠢货
A clueless mutt.
和一个自大的贱人
And a stuck-up bitch.
锁住他们
Collar them!
我觉得瞪着她无法帮我们摆脱困境
I really don't think glaring at her is gonna get us anywhere.
我只是不敢相信
I just can't believe you
你竟然禁受不住这种流浪者的诱惑
fell for some half-baked Rover seduction.
她救过我的命
She saved my life.
她还扒光了你  抢了你的东西
She also stripped you naked and robbed you.
要不是她对你大抛媚眼
That wouldn't have happened
就不会落得这个下场了
if she hadn't batted her well-trained lashes at you.
什么  拜托  她不是我喜欢的类型
What? Please. She's not my type.
你的耳朵又红了
Your ears are turning red again.
我叔叔提醒过我  说流浪者绝不可信
My uncle warned me Rovers can never be trusted.
无论他们说什么  他们都有自己的目的
No matter what they say, they always have an agenda.
当你一辈子都要被别人评头论足时
When you've spent your life being judged for who you are,
尽量努力不对他人抱有成见
you try to keep an open mind about people.
你们俩吵架就像一对侏儒老夫妻
You two fight like a couple of old Gnomes.
埃蕾崔娅  听我说
Eretria, listen,
你不清楚其中的利害关系
you don't know what's at stake here.
放我们走  把精灵石还给我
Set us free and give me back the Elfstones.
要是恶魔来攻击你
A Demon attack is probably
那或许就大快人心了
the best thing that could happen to you.
别逼我从马上下来
Don't make me get off this horse.
骂她就是你的计划吗
This is your plan? Insult her?
-听我的就好  -好吧
- Just follow my lead. - All right.
你想再比一场吗  来吧
You wanted a rematch, let's do it.
算了吧
I'll pass.
你被一个精灵族女孩给吓到了  对吗
You intimidated by an Elvin girl, is that it?
让你的人把我脖子上的链子解开
Have your man take off my collar,
-我还要把剑...-别这样
- and I'll need a sword... - Oh, come on!
还以为她不会闭嘴呢
Thought she'd never shut up.
把她放到我的马背上
Put her on the back of my horse.
这样的比试太不公平了
That wasn't even close to a fair fight!
这个世界本来就不公平
Well, the world isn't fair.
你为什么要这么做
Why are you doing this?
如她所说  因为我是个流浪者
Like she said, I'm a Rover.
我觉得应该还有别的理由
I think there's more to you than that.
你错了
You're wrong.
都散开
Hey! Get out of there.
这位是我父亲  赛法罗
Meet my father, Cephalo.
为什么他像狗一样拴在这里
Why is he collared like a dog?
解开
Untie him.
这不是我们的待客之道
This isn't how we treat a guest.
原谅我的女儿
Forgive my daughter.
她的脑子比起她的美貌可差远了
Her brain is no match for her beauty.
-和我一起的精灵族女孩...-她很安全
- The Elvin girl I was with... - She's safe.
希望你能放我和安波莉走
It would be better if Amberle and I left.
我们得回去  有位朋友需要我们的帮助
We need to get back. A friend needs our help.
他觉得有恶魔在追赶他们
He think Demons are hunting them.
恶魔
Demons?
你可真有想象力  不是吗
You have quite an imagination, don't you?
放心  你和你的朋友在这里很安全
Rest assured, you and your friend are well-protected here.
不知怎的  这话并不能让我更安心
Somehow that doesn't make me feel safer.
没什么好怕的  威尔
There's nothing to be afraid of, Wil.
我们和你是一样的
We're the same as you.
我们的愿望是一致的  都是和平与繁荣
We all want the same thing... peace and prosperity.
我们沙迪谷虽然不富有
We don't have much in the Vale,
但我们从不通过盗窃致富
but we never resort to stealing.
精灵让我们别无选择
The Elves left us no choice.
他们才是真正的窃贼
They're the real thieves.
将我们从家园驱赶出来
Drove us from our homes.
你用不着跟我找借口
You don't have to justify yourself to me.
我只是你的犯人
I'm just your prisoner.
我知道你的难处  威尔
I know it's been hard for you, Wil.
精灵把你当人类  人类又当你是精灵
Too human for the Elves, too Elvin for the Humans.
但是这里能够接受你
But here you would be accepted.
你是在邀请我加入流浪者吗
Are you asking me to become a Rover?
我给你的远不止如此
I'm offering you much more than that.
我们是家人
We're a family.
我是在给你机会成为我们中的一员
I'm giving you the opportunity to join it.
我知道你想当一名医师
I understand you want to be a healer.
你的才能在这里是很宝贵的
Your skills would be valued here.
-感谢你的提议  可是...-别急着回答
- I appreciate the offer, but... - Don't answer now.
四处走走
Walk around.
认识一下大家
Get to know everybody.
今晚宴会上再答复我
Give me your answer tonight at the feast.
那个精灵女孩准备好了吗
Is the Elf girl ready?
没有
No.
为什么
And why is that?
听着...
Look...
卖了她  让她当奴隶
sell her, make her a slave.
随你怎么处置
Do whatever you want.
我都不在乎
I don't care.
可是呢
But?
我杀人是为了生存  不是为了取乐
I kill to survive, not for sport.
太好了
Amazing.
我把我毕生所学都教给你了
I teach you everything I know
而你还是每次都会犯蠢
and yet you still come up stupid every time.
埃蕾崔娅  我要你演场戏令他信服
Eretria, I need you to put on a convincing show.
除非那个小杂种觉得你真会杀了她
Unless the half-breed thinks you're willing to gut her,
否则他是不会告诉我如何开启精灵石的
he won't tell me how to unlock those Stones.
而我真的  真的很想要那些石头
And I really, really want those Stones.
等你得到了你想要的之后呢
And once you get what you want?
她就交给你处置  如何你继续忤逆我
Then you'll do to her what I'll do to you
那死的人就会是你
if you continue to disobey me.
我想从这个角度来看
So, I guess at that point, yeah.
应该就不违背你为了生存而杀人了吧
I guess it will be killing for survival.
你的头怎么样了  公主
How's your head, Princess?
你会在乎吗
What do you care?
-等等  威尔呢  -他没事
- Wait, where's Wil? - Safe.
听着  我之前没说谎
Look, I wasn't lying before.
-我得马上回...-知道  知道
- I need to get back to... - Yeah. Yeah.
回阿博隆去
Back to Arborlon.
这话留着说给别人听吧
Save that for someone who cares.
你真的很讨厌精灵  对吗
You really don't like Elves, do you?
对
No.
事实上上次和你的冲突
And the fact that it's a shock to you
令我对他们更加讨厌了
makes me hate them even more.
你有两个选择
Here are your choices.
要么穿上这个和我决一生死
Put these on and we fight to the death.
要么揍我一拳  然后逃跑
Or punch me in the face and make a run for it.
我为什么要做这两件事
Why would I do either of those things?
做其中一件  因为你想活下去
One, because you want to live,
做另一件  因为你想死吧
and the other, because you want to die?
我是不是该觉得
What, and I'm supposed to
你帮助我是出于
trust that you're helping me out of, what?
你内心的善良呢
The goodness of your heart?
杀不杀你  什么时候动手
When and if I kill you,
都是我自己的决定  不是他的
I want it to be my choice, not his.
这不是我要的人生
This is not gonna be my life.
我不能离开威尔
Well, I can't leave Wil.
我们得回去找我们的伙伴
We have to get back to our friend.
你没听懂吗
You don't really get it, do you?
要是你想在这里活下去
If you want to survive in this world,
就必须照看好自己
you need to start taking care of yourself,
因为可没人会照看你
because no one's gonna do that for you.
也许你是对的
Maybe you're right.
但我有个更好的主意
But I have a better idea.
放轻松  威尔
Relax, Wil.
你朋友没事的  我保证
Your friend's in good hands, I promise.
她很快就会过来的
She'll be joining us shortly.
对了  关于我的邀约
Now, about my offer,
你考虑过了吗
have you considered it?
我考虑过了...
I have...
恐怕我不能答应
and I'm afraid I can't accept.
我说过  我得去找我的朋友
Like I said, I need to get back to my friend.
可惜了
Pity.
这个邀约可不是谁都有的
But this life isn't for everyone.
威尔  这是陷阱
Wil, it's a trap!
放了他
Let him go!
你根本没计划吧
You didn't think this through, did you?
闭嘴
Shut up.
看来我低估了你  姑娘
It appears I've underestimated you, young lady.
或者我高估了你
Or overestimated you.
放他走  不然你女儿就要死
Let him go or your daughter dies.
拜托了
Please.
别这样
Don't.
我求你了
I'm begging you.
拜托了  求你别这样
Please. Please, don't.
我...
I...
住手  住手  拜托了
Stop, stop! Please!
你要什么就说  我会照做的
Just tell me what you want, and I'll do it.
张开手
Open your hand.
什么
What?
沙娜拉人  我听说过你父亲的故事
I've heard the stories about your father, Shannara,
但和大多数人不同  我相信这些故事
but unlike most folks, I actually believe them.
你展示一下如何使用这些石头
Now, you show me how to use these Stones
我就不杀她
and I won't kill her.
听我说  这些石头只是石头而已
Listen to me, these Stones are just stones.
要她死还是活  威尔
Does she live or does she die, Wil?
我发誓  即使石头有魔法
I swear to you, even if they were magic,
-我也不会用  -答错了
- I don't know how to use... - Wrong answer!
别别  我不知道怎么使用...
No, no, no, no! I have no idea how to use...
怒鬼  快跑
Fury! Run!
安波莉
Amberle!
他还有呼吸吗
Is he breathing?
你去担心你的人吧  威尔我来照顾
You worry about your own people, I'll take care of Wil.
姑娘你想干什么  想杀了我们两个吗
What are you gonna do, girl? Kill us both?
你已经证明你做不到这一点了
I think you've already proven you aren't up to the task.
我觉得杀了你就足够了
Actually, I think I'll just kill you.
很好
Fine.
把石头给我
Just give me the Stones
我放你们两个离开
and I'll let you both walk away.
亚拉农
Allanon?
你们现在应该在阿博隆
You two are supposed to be in Arborlon.
威尔坚持要救你
Well, Wil insisted on trying to save you.
他用了精灵石
He used the Elfstones.
他拼死救了我
He almost died saving me.
责备自己是没用的
Blaming yourself is worthless.
精灵石是他必须肩负的重任
The Stones are his burden to bear.
这只是开始
This is only the beginning.
以后还会有
More will come.
你为什么觉得我和威尔可以阻止他们
And what makes you think Wil and I can do anything to stop them?
因为这是你的使命  崇高的使命
Because you share a destiny. A greater purpose.
要是你错了呢
Yeah, and if you're wrong?
如今的事态
The events leading us to this moment
在几百年前就有了端倪
have been unfurling for centuries.
威尔会躺在这里  因为石头已经知道他是谁
Wil lies here because he has yet to reconcile who he is
而他自己却还没有明白
with who the Stones already know him to be.
你参加选拔赛  想要明白人生的意义
You ran the Gauntlet trying to find your place in life
而命运已经为你找到了意义
and yet destiny had already found it for you.
这一切
Everything, all of this,
并不是因为你而发生的
is not happening because of you,
他们是冲你来的
it is happening to you.
你们越早明白这一点越好
And the sooner you accept that, the better.
冷静  冷静
Calm down. Calm down.
没事的
It's okay.
怒鬼呢
The Fury?
被你用精灵石消灭了
You used to Elfstones to destroy it.
带公主去阿博隆吧
My instructions were to take the Princess to Arborlon.
已经浪费很多时间了
Come, we've wasted enough time.
我身体没事了  谢谢
I'm feeling fine, thanks.
这是恶魔做的吗
Did Demons do this?
你没事吧
Are you okay?
你在做什么
What are you doing?
里面可能有恶魔
There could be a Demon in there.
里面也可能有人需要我们的帮助
Or there could be someone who needs our help.
告诉我们你的名字
Tell us your name.
班登
Bandon.
谁把你关在里面的  班登
Who locked you in the cellar, Bandon?
我父母
My parents.
为什么关你
Why would they do that?
这不重要了  他们都死了
It doesn't matter now. They're dead.
不是吗
Aren't they?
是的
Yes.
我听到了恶魔的声音
I heard the Demons first.
然后是我父母的尖叫声
Then my parents' screams.
我帮不了他们
I couldn't help them.
我救不了他们
I couldn't save them.
这不怪你
It's not your fault.
不怪你
It's not.
带他一起去阿博隆吧  那里很安全
He's coming with us to Arborlon. He'll be safe there.
我觉得不好
I think that's a bad idea.
那什么才好
And what's a good one?
把他留在这里  跟他父母挂在一起吗
Leaving him here, chained up with his dead parents?
我读不出这孩子的想法
I cannot read this boy's thoughts.
他不是隐瞒了自己会魔法
Either he's hiding magic
就是不知道自己会魔法
or he doesn't know he has magic.
我看不透他
Without reading him,
就不能保证你的安全
I cannot guarantee your safety.
他跟我们走  就这么定了
He's coming with us and that's final.
来吧  你跟我们一起走
Come on. You're coming with me.
你要去哪儿
Where are you off to?
我们说好的  我把威尔交给你就放我走
I delivered you Wil and that was our deal, okay?
现在我要有多远走多远
Now I'm getting as far from here as possible.
现在石头和小伙都没有了
I have neither the Stones nor the boy.
这不是我的问题
That's not my problem.
这是什么
What's this?
你从那个精灵族姑娘手上拿的吧
You got this from that Elvin girl, didn't you?
既然她戴着这个  看来她身份不一般啊
And if she was wearing this, she just wasn't any girl.
你这么漂亮  却这么让人失望
So beautiful, yet so disappointing.
你永远不会放我走了
You're never gonna let me go.
听着
Listen.
精灵石等于自由
Elfstones... equal... freedom.
再骗我  就杀了你
Lie to me again and I'll kill you.
公主
The Princess.
别担心  这里很安全
Don't worry, you're safe here.
抱歉  你没事吧
I'm... I'm sorry. Are you okay?
没事
I'm fine.
给他食物和衣服
Make sure he's fed and clothed.
听他的吩咐
Anything he needs.
我们有内奸  因此恶魔
There is an enemy within these walls.
才会在派丽雅那儿找到安波莉
That is how the Demon knew to find Amberle at Pyria's.
守卫必须加倍
You must double your security.
绝不能让公主落单
The Princess must never be left alone.
明白了
Understood.
安波莉
Amberle!
安德叔叔
Uncle Ander!
谢天谢地
Thank God.
你吓死我了
You scared the hell out of me.
我自己也吓死了
I scared the hell out of myself.
精灵议会成员都在国王的会议室里了
The Elvin Council is gathered in the King's chamber,
大多数成员都将
and most of them still blame you
艾尔奎斯圣树的问题怪罪于你
for what's happening to the Ellcrys,
恐怕只有我一人欢迎你了
so I'm afraid the warm welcome ends with me.
等等  安波莉怎么不直接去艾尔奎斯圣树那
Wait, why isn't Amberle going straight to the Ellcrys?
因为作为神选之子
Because she abandoned her sacred duty
她背弃了神圣的职责
as a member of the Chosen.
只有精灵议会
Only the Elvin Council
才能批准她重入圣所
can grant her permission to reenter the Sanctuary.
真是疯了
That's crazy.
所以我们得去见议会  告诉他们我们的见闻
That's why we have to address the Council, tell them what we saw.
你看...
Uh, look...
我说过会送你安全回家
I told you I'd get you home safely,
你已经到家了
but that was it.
是的  你做到了
Yes, you did. You...
你遵守了诺言
you kept your promise.
再见  威尔·欧姆斯福德
Good-bye, Wil Ohmsford.
再见  安波莉·艾雷瑟迪尔
Good-bye, Amberle Elessedil.
让我猜猜
Let me guess.
你要说我犯了一个大错
You're gonna tell me I'm making a terrible mistake,
我让安波莉失望了
that I'm letting down Amberle
背弃了我对四境肩负的责任
and abandoning my duty to the Four Lands.
差不多吧
That pretty much covers it.
我不会让精灵石把我变成我父亲那样
I won't let those Elfstones turn me into my father.
我帮你保留这些  直到我们的命运再度交会
Then I shall hold on to these until our paths cross again.
真有意思
It's been interesting.
实际上并不是
Actually, it hasn't.
从头到尾就是个噩梦
It's been a total nightmare from start to finish.
我的旅程到此为止
This is where my journey ends.
威尔  等等
Wil, wait!
你不能离开安波莉
You can't leave Amberle.
亚拉农派你来的吗
Did Allanon put you up to this?
别担心  她没事的
Don't worry, she'll be fine.
不  她有事
No, she won't!
班登  我的任务完成了  好吗
Bandon, I'm done here, okay?
她安然无恙地到家了
She's home, safe and sound.
我遵守了诺言  现在结束了
I did what I said I'd do and now I'm done.
我不能让你走
I can't let you do that.
要是你不陪安波莉去避风堡
If you don't go with Amberle to Safehold,
会有糟糕的事发生
something terrible will happen.
你怎么知道避风堡的
How do you know about Safehold?
拜托了...  威尔...
Please... Wil...
你必须相信我
you have to trust me.
召集精灵议会是为了讨论艾尔奎斯圣树的危机
The Elvin Council is called to discuss the crisis of the Ellcrys.
亚拉农
Allanon.
艾尔奎斯圣树即将枯萎
The Ellcrys is dying.
随着它的叶子凋落
As it sheds its leaves, a Demon army forms,
会有一支恶魔大军要毁灭世界
preparing to unleash its evil upon our world.
我能保证恶魔是真的
Let me assure you, these Demons are real.
他们不止杀了神选之子  还杀了我姑姑
Not only did they kill the Chosen but also my aunt,
派丽雅
Pyria.
艾尔奎斯圣树将孕育一枚种子
The Ellcrys will bear a seed.
神选之子的一员必须将种子
That seed must be carried by one of the Chosen
带到避风堡
to a place called Safehold.
并将其投入血火之中
There it will be immersed in the Bloodfire.
如此种子才能得以回归
Only then can it be returned
艾尔奎斯圣树才能重生
and the Ellcrys can be reborn.
作为唯一幸存的神选之子
As the only remaining member of the Chosen,
这个重任就落在你们公主身上了
the burden of this quest falls upon your princess...
安波莉
Amberle.
我父亲告诉我魔法已经失传多年
My father taught me that magic died years ago.
我错了
I was wrong.
现在他却要我们去相信这种神话
Yet now he asks us to believe in fairy tales.
这些故事只是其他种族的阴谋
For all we know, this is nothing but a plot by the other Races
为了让我们屈服
to bring us to our knees.
有阴谋的只有岱达摩
The Dagda Mor is the only one plotting here.
恶魔是你们的敌人
Demons are your enemies.
而她是你们唯一的希望
And she is your only hope.
我们不能把四境和精灵族的命运托付给
We cannot put the fate of the Four Lands and the Elvin people
这个德鲁伊和我侄女
in the hands of this Druid and my niece,
我爱我侄女
whom I love dearly,
但她一度逃离了自己的使命
but who has run away from her duties once already.
安波莉没有逃离
Amberle didn't run away.
她是为了保护你们
She was trying to protect you.
迪尔顿指挥官  赶他出去
Commander Tilton, escort him out now.
根据精灵族规
By Elvin law, you are not to lay a hand
你不能动皇室成员
upon a member of the royal family.
这个半人的杂种可不是皇室成员
I guarantee that this half-breed is not a member of this family.
他的确不是
No, he is not.
但他是沙娜拉人的末裔
He is the last son of Shannara.
让他接着说
Let him speak!
谢谢你
Thank you.
听着  我知道你们在想什么
Look, I know what you're all thinking.
你们觉得这一切太匪夷所思了
That the things you're hearing are too incredible to be true.
但魔法和恶魔是真的
But magic and demons are real.
我亲眼见过它们
I have seen them with my own eyes.
老实说  我当时只想逃跑
Quite frankly, all I want to do is run away.
但我遇到了安波莉
Then I met Amberle.
她可能也很害怕
She might have been frightened,
但她非常勇敢
but she's also incredibly brave.
她没必要回来
She didn't have to come back,
但她回来了
but she did,
为了你们  为了她所爱的人而回
for all of you, the people she loves.
要是问我谁能拯救四境
And if I had to put my faith in anyone
我只信任她可以
to save the Four Lands, it would be her.
别挖苦我
Don't even say it.
我想这是你的
I think these belong to you.
现在
Now...
请问各位尊敬的议员
I put the question to you, esteemed members of the Council.
你们是否允许安波莉重回圣所
Will you allow Amberle to return to the Sanctuary
履行她神圣的使命
and fulfill her sacred duty?
是的
Aye.
安波莉·艾雷瑟迪尔
Amberle Elessedil,
你曾背弃神选之子的使命
you turned your back on the Chosen
背弃了对艾尔奎斯圣树的职责
and your duties to the Ellcrys.
是的
I did.
现在你希望带着种子去血火吗
And now you wish to carry its seed to the Bloodfire.
是的
I do.
根据法典
According to the Codex,
你必须获取艾尔奎斯圣树的认可
the Ellcrys must be satisfied
才能去完成这项使命
of your commitment to this quest.
如果你通过了试炼  它会给你种子
If you pass the test, it will give you the seed.
如果你失败了
If you fail...
你会死亡
you will die.
你愿意进入树中吗
Are you willing to enter the tree?
我愿意
I am.
要是我能陪你一起进去就好了
I wish I could go in there with you.
我明白
I know.
谢谢你回来
Thanks for coming back.
我是怕亚拉农孤单
I figured Allanon would get lonely.
而且我发现自己
And it turns out I enjoy
挺喜欢每天直面几次生死的
staring death in the face at least once a day.
你耳朵又红了
Your ears are turning red again.
沙娜拉传奇
第一季  第三集
本字幕首发于字幕组网站
www.ZiMuZu.tv 欢迎交流
翻译  红枫Gabriel
翻译  猛回头
校对  歌谣
时间轴  JimmyBeck 姜姜 西·查
后期 吉吉    总监  歌谣
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    ustvboom
了解最新影视字幕发布信息